# **Shivam Sitapara**

#### **Biomedical Engineer**

North Wales, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Shivam-Sitapara/a7c60af9b370bc52

Recent graduate from Drexel University with a major in Biomedical Engineering and 1.5 years of professional experience. Currently seeking a position as an engineer in technical sales, consultation, research and development, product design, etc.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Brain Machine Interface Senior Design Project**

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA - September 2015 to May 2016

- Produced a proof-of-concept BMI design to restore lower limb movement in paraplegics.
- Developed a software program to decode neural signals and utilize them to stimulate the spinal cord.
- Designed a circuit to send the proper current to the desired areas of an electrode array/spinal cord.
- Discussed progress and future plans with senior design team, advisor, and PhD students weekly.

### **Engineering R&D Co-op**

Rex Medical - Conshohocken, PA - April 2015 to September 2015

- Developed and executed test protocols and innovative design prototypes to tend to customer needs.
- Fabricated thrombectomy prototypes that were tested and evaluated in animal and cadaver labs.
- Guided team in recommendations in product development, FMEA, and root cause analysis.
- Obtained experience following several ISO and GLP/GCP/GMP federal standards and regulations.

#### Osteoarthritis Junior Design Project

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA - September 2014 to December 2014

- Utilize current solutions and recent advancements to develop a more efficient solution to osteoarthritis.
- · Research current patents relating to the design as well as FDA pathway for design development.
- Follow engineering standards by creating a device master record, design history file, and design plan.

#### Endoscopy R&D Co-op

Boston Scientific - Marlborough, MA - April 2014 to September 2014

- Participated in offsite animal and bench labs to evaluate current prototypes on clinical field performance.
- Worked collaboratively with team to rebuild and redefine the existing endoscopic navigation process.
- Designed complex tests including all methods, equipment, and fixturing.
- Demonstrated statistical reliability and repeatability of tests for assessing device performance.

## **Biomedical Suite Project Intern**

Polysciences Inc - Warrington, PA - April 2013 to September 2013

- Assisted in the preparation of construction for a new biomedical laboratory.
- Worked in a team to make sure the synthesis of products such as lotions and sanitizers met specifications.
- Maintained chemical inventory database and handled chemical waste by following protocol.

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Science in Biomedical Engineering**

Drexel University - Philadelphia, PA 2016

## **SKILLS**

Microsoft Office (10+ years), Autocad (4 years), Solid Works (3 years), Creo Parametric (5 years), Pro/ Engineer (5 years), Minitab (2 years), ImageJ (2 years), Matlab (5 years)